Finding Aid for Woman’s Study Club of Ypsilanti records, 1897-1999
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Woman’s Study Club of Ypsilanti records 1897-1999
Woman’s Study Club of Ypsilanti (Mich.)
5 linear feet.
85468 Bp 2
Originally formed as auxiliary to Ladies Literary Club. Minutes, scrapbooks, program books, and other organizational materials.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated by the organization (donor no. 6128 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
In 1896, the Ladies Literary Club of Ypsilanti sponsored an auxiliary organization, the Study Club. The first meeting of the Club was held in the Ladies Library building in January 1897. The purpose of the Club was to meet and listen to a prepared lecture on a subject of topical interest given by one of the Club's members. In 1903, the Study Club formed its own auxiliary, the Woman's Club, which held its first meeting in 1904. In 1924, the two groups merged to form the Woman's Study Club of Ypsilanti.
The records of the Woman's Study Club of Ypsilanti include a history of the organization written in 1980, minute books of the organization, programs, membership materials, and scrapbooks of club activities.
Subjects:
Arts--Michigan--Ypsilanti--Societies, etc.; Ladies Literary Club (Ypsilanti, Mich.); Women--Michigan--Ypsilanti--Societies and clubs.; Ypsilanti (Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
- History
  - 1980 (Box 1)
- Secretary's Minutes
  - Study Club
    - 1897-1898 (Box 1)
    - 1904-1908 (Box 1)
  - Ypsilanti Study Club
    - 1908-1924, 7 volumes (Box 1)
  - Ypsilanti Woman's Club (auxiliary to Ypsilanti Study Club)
    - 1914-1924, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - Woman's Study Club of Ypsilanti (renamed from Ypsilanti Study Club)
    - 1924-1954, 7 volumes (Box 1)
    - 1954-1999, 6 volumes and 6 booklets (Box 2)
- Conventions and special events
  - Michigan Centennial
    - Correspondence and miscellanea, 1937 (Box 2)
    - Scrapbooks, 1937, 2 volumes (Box 2)
  - Fourteenth Conference of the Cause and Cure of War, Washington DC, 1939 (Box 2)
  - General Federation of Women's Clubs, Triennial Convention, Detroit, 1953 (Box 2)
- Program Books/Membership materials
  - Study Club (later Woman's Study Club) (Box 3)
    - 1897-1999 (Box 3)
      (some years missing)
  - Ypsilanti Woman's Club
    - 1904-1924 (Box 3)
  - Resolutions and letters of respect for deceased members (Box 3)
- Scrapbooks
  - 1930-1952, 4 volumes (Box 4)
  - 1952-1992, 4 volumes (Box 5)